<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[dbushell.com]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[David Bushell’s Web Design & Front-end Development Blog]]></description>
    <link>https://dbushell.com</link>
    <generator>dbushell.com</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 07:48:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dbushell.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <author><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></author>
    <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
    <webMaster><![CDATA[hi@dbushell.com (David Bushell)]]></webMaster>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[I watched Iron Fist and coded CSS 👈]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>They have nothing in common.
Well, aside from entertaining my weekend. I’m just bad at blog titles and I’m fed up of writing nonsense like “CSS modularity; theory and practice”. My draft title, which let’s face it, nobody is clicking.
Iron Fist is ‘aight I guess. I’m 7 episodes deep and I’m still awake which is an […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2017/04/03/i-watched-iron-fist-and-coded-css/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2017/04/03/i-watched-iron-fist-and-coded-css/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Web Security and Cloudflare]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>I’ve never had to deal with SSL certificates before. That’s always been someone else’s responsibility. Being ignorant of the technical details, the idea of setting up SSL/TLS wrong scares me. The idea of my visitors seeing those browser warnings scares me even more. And they’re getting scarier by the year.


I listened to an episode of […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2017/02/17/web-security-and-cloudflare/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2017/02/17/web-security-and-cloudflare/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[React as a Static Site Generator]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>Two years ago I converted my website from WordPress to a static build process. It has served me well but the final process was rather messy. Hacks and plumbing to get Metalsmith plugins working my way didn’t helped.
Time for a new project!
Abstract: rebuild my website using React as the template engine for a bespoke static […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2017/02/13/react-as-a-static-site-generator/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2017/02/13/react-as-a-static-site-generator/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Working with Promises]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>JavaScript promises are a handy way to write asynchronous code. It’s common to have multiple promises resolve in parallel or series.
Let’s say you have several functions that return a promise:
function act1() {
  return new Promise((resolve, reject) &#x3D;&gt; {
    // do something that might reject...
    resolve();
  });
}

It’s easy […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2016/12/16/resolving-javascript-promises-sequentially-without-nesting/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2016/12/16/resolving-javascript-promises-sequentially-without-nesting/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[My thoughts on React]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been playing with React for some time now. React is:

“A JavaScript library for building user interfaces”.

Unlike other libraries something about React just clicked with me. Back in October a client project came along that presented a golden opportunity to develop a web app. I decided to use React, and I now consider myself comfortable […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2016/12/02/my-thoughts-on-react/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2016/12/02/my-thoughts-on-react/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Building a Shopify Theme]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>Shopify is an ecommerce platform that offers themeable store fronts online. I worked alongside the wonderful folks at Studio Tangerine to develop a Shopify theme. I’ve documented interesting aspects of the process below.


Getting started
If you’re familiar with my workflow it will be no surprised that I first translated the design into static HTML &amp;amp; CSS […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2016/10/10/building-a-shopify-theme/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2016/10/10/building-a-shopify-theme/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Colour Accessibility]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>“Accessiblity” isn’t a scary word but many web folks shy away from it. Perhaps because the W3C guidelines are a little scary. The reality is website accessibility affects us all. Not just those of us who cross the threshold into a medically diagnosed condition.
“I want to see like the colour blind” is a Chrome plugin […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2016/09/01/colour-accessibility/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2016/09/01/colour-accessibility/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Building a WordPress Theme]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>I was delighted when Base Creative asked me to help build a beautifully designed website on WordPress. It’s always a joy to work with Base Creative knowing that my role is made easier by the care and attention they deliver.


In this review I’ll showcase a few of the defining techniques and challenges that made this […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2016/07/14/building-a-wordpress-theme/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2016/07/14/building-a-wordpress-theme/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[New Origins]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>Greetings! It’s been a while, hasn’t it? The last few months were busy for me. That’s a good thing I suppose, I certainly need to earn a living.
The only real downside of plentiful client work is the lack of time for my own projects. One of those, codename: “Origin”, is my personal front-end starter kit. […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2016/07/12/new-origins/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2016/07/12/new-origins/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[CSS only Responsive Tables]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>Four years ago I shared an idea to make tabular data responsive. Browser support was experimental and the workarounds were extremely hacky. I revisited the technique this week, cleaned it up, and I am pleased to say all modern browsers work perfectly.
See the full demo on CodePen



Here’s what basic overflow looks like:


And if you want […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2016/03/04/css-only-responsive-tables/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2016/03/04/css-only-responsive-tables/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Be careful with your viewBox]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>In Sara Soueidan’s article: SVG Style Inheritance and the ‘Flash of Unstyled SVG’, Sara explains the importance of having width, height, and viewBox attributes on SVG elements. This reminded me of two issues I ran into last week building my new design.
I have an SVG sprite for social icons:

  
  .svg-icon  { […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2016/03/01/be-careful-with-your-viewbox/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2016/03/01/be-careful-with-your-viewbox/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[A Bit of a New Look]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>I redesigned my website!

This iteration has taken longer than usual because the visual changes are much more dramatic. I’m really pleased with the results:


It’s been two years since I last updated the design. That is a record because it’s usually an annual tradition. Past updates include: 2014, 2013, 2012, and 2011. Last year I improved […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2016/02/29/a-bit-of-a-new-look/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2016/02/29/a-bit-of-a-new-look/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[CSS Framework for PartsGiant]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p> PartsGiant is a soon to launch e-commerce store based in Michigan, USA. 
I was hired to build the PartsGiant front-end CSS framework and HTML templates. The work would be done in stages throughout the year. This required flexibility on my part and scalability in the codebase I developed.
I’ve always championed the idea of maintainable, […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2016/01/04/css-framework-for-partsgiant/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2016/01/04/css-framework-for-partsgiant/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[My Year in Review]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>All considered, 2015 has been a good year!
My highlight for sure was moving into my new flat. The whole searching, buying, and decorating process took way longer than I imagined. Because of this I didn’t take on as many large projects, but I did manage to find enough freelance work to keep me going.
January
What better […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2015/12/30/2015-in-review/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2015/12/30/2015-in-review/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Tales WordPress theme is now free!]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>Tales is a WordPress theme I developed early last year to show that responsive design and legacy browser support are not mutually exclusive.


For the few months that I sold Tales it provided a small but welcome side income (considering my lack of advertising). Today I’m happy to announce that Tales is now free to download […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2015/11/12/tales-wordpress-theme-now-free/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2015/11/12/tales-wordpress-theme-now-free/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Accelerated Mobile Pages]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>The AMP Project is an initiative by Google to improve the “mobile web”.
Accelerated Mobile Pages are an alternate version of their corresponding, canonical web page. They’re still HTML but limited — check the spec. The best way to understand Accelerated Mobile Pages is to see them in action:


The BBC News website has implemented AMP, screenshotted […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2015/10/20/accelerated-mobile-pages/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2015/10/20/accelerated-mobile-pages/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[September Update]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>Good afternoon! So it’s been a while since I last blogged. Turns out buying a home takes longer than I imagined!
When I left London in 2012, I moved back in with my parents  (temporarily) to embark upon a freelance career. Work has been steady, not easy, but rewarding and I’m much happier out of […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2015/09/07/september-update/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2015/09/07/september-update/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Real-Life Responsive Web Design]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>Last week I had the opportunity to read “Real-Life Responsive Web Design”, the fifth book in the Smashing Book series.


Usually with books like this I will skip to the chapters that immediately catch my eye. This time was different, they all sounded fascinating — and they were! I read the book cover to cover in […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2015/07/27/smashing-book-5/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2015/07/27/smashing-book-5/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Social Profiles]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>My website navigation now links to my GitHub and CodePen profiles, alongside Twitter. A long overdue change. It was embarrassing to be rocking the Google+ link. I never used Google+, I don’t even use Facebook, but it was useful to get my face alongside search results. That feature disappeared some time ago and thus the […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2015/06/26/social-profiles/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2015/06/26/social-profiles/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Order: HTML vs CSS]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[<p>Content should follow a logical top-to-bottom order within HTML. CSS is used to change the visual presentation of this content across different viewports.
On small viewports — mobile phones for example — a vertical layout that mimics the HTML order is generally a safe default. For wider viewports it is common to introduce more complex layout […]</p>]]></description>
  <link>https://dbushell.com/2015/06/01/order-html-vs-css/</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dbushell.com/2015/06/01/order-html-vs-css/</guid>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Bushell]]></dc:creator>
  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
